<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on P4 REEU</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on P4 REEU</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 Natalie G. Nelson</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Nelson and collaborators receive NSF grant to study connections between freshwater discharges and coastal algal blooms</title>
      <link>/post/20180910_nsf-rapid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20180910_nsf-rapid/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Natalie Nelson (PI, NC State), Dr. Edward Phlips (Co-PI, UF), and Dr. Eric Milbrandt (Co-PI, Sanibel-Captiva Conservation Foundation) were awarded a RAPID grant from the National Science Foundation&amp;rsquo;s Environmental Engineering program for their project entitled, &amp;ldquo;Coastal consequences of engineered water control systems: the role of freshwater discharges in Florida&amp;rsquo;s ongoing harmful algal bloom crises.&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alice Alonso wins 1st Place in the Envisioning Research competition</title>
      <link>/post/20180801_alice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20180801_alice/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Alice Alonso, Visiting Postdoctoral Scholar in the Biosystems Analytics Lab, wins &lt;strong&gt;First Place&lt;/strong&gt; in the Faculty &amp;amp; Staff category of the NC State Envisioning Research photography competition for her submission, &lt;em&gt;A Meeting of River &amp;amp; Sea&lt;/em&gt; (shown above).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lise Montefiore&#39;s research showcased in the CALS Student Spotlight</title>
      <link>/post/20180627_lise/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20180627_lise/</guid>
      <description>NC State College of Agricultural and Life Sciences News spotlighted Lise Montefiore, Biosystems Analytics Lab PhD Student, for her research on the use of data analytics to identify vulnerable estuaries in the Southeast U.S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lise Montefiore earns 2nd Place for her poster at the NC State Graduate Student Research Symposium</title>
      <link>/post/20180321_lise/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20180321_lise/</guid>
      <description>Lise Montefiore, Biosystems Analytics Lab PhD Student, wins &lt;strong&gt;Second Place&lt;/strong&gt; in the Agricultural Sciences and Natural Resources category of the NC State Graduate Student Research Symposium for her poster, &lt;em&gt;Coupling climate, land use, and sea level rise projections to identify threatened estuaries in North Carolina&lt;/em&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sam Blackman takes 3rd Place in the NC Water Resources Research Institute student poster competition</title>
      <link>/post/20180315_sam/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20180315_sam/</guid>
      <description>Sam Blackman, Undergraduate Research Assistant in the Biosystems Analytics Lab, wins &lt;strong&gt;Third Place&lt;/strong&gt; in the NC Water Resources Research Institute student poster competition for his poster, &lt;em&gt;Quantifying seasonal variability of dissolved oxygen and pH in brackish habitats of the South Atlantic and Gulf of Mexico&lt;/em&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natalie Nelson selected for the New Faces of Engineering Class of 2018 by ASABE</title>
      <link>/post/20180228_natalie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20180228_natalie/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Natalie Nelson, PI of the Biosystems Analytics Lab, was chosen by the American Society of Agricultural and Biological Engineers for the New Faces of Engineering Class of 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>