<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on P4 REEU</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on P4 REEU</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 Natalie G. Nelson</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How do environmental conditions in poultry barns impact poultry performance?</title>
      <link>/project/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project1/</guid>
      <description>This project will seek to answer the question: how do environmental conditions in poultry barns impact poultry performance? At present, monitoring data collected in poultry houses are largely leveraged to address basic questions regarding the functionality of environmental control systems, such as whether a house has exceeded a temperature threshold, but these data yield the potential to address far more consequential questions than whether an environmental control system has met specifications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis and interpretation of agricultural wastewater treatment data</title>
      <link>/project/project6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project6/</guid>
      <description>There is significant interest in designing wastewater treatment systems for animal agriculture, especially for the swine industry. Adsorption is one such technology that is practical and highly relevant to the swine industry. However, design of an adsorption system involves collection, analyses, and interpretation of laboratory data. Therefore, students working on this project will collect and analyze the data with the goal of developing design metrics for adsorption systems for swine lagoons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparative analysis of U.S. and Chinese swine and poultry production systems</title>
      <link>/project/project5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project5/</guid>
      <description>The P4 fellow who works on this project will analyze data collected from a range of different swine and poultry barns in China, and perform a comparative analysis to identify areas in which domestic and Chinese systems diverge. The P4 fellow will work closely with our Chinese collaborators at Zhejiang University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating long-term relationships between swine waste chemistry and ammonium deposition</title>
      <link>/project/project3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project3/</guid>
      <description>The P4 fellow who works on this project will analyze long-term data on swine waste chemistry and management to identify existing trends with swine waste composition and ammonium deposition on the surrounding landscape. The overall goal of this project will be to produce data-driven insight on how swine waste management can be enhanced to mitigate environmental impacts. This project addresses the Grand Challenges Facing Animal Production of (1) producing animal proteins in an economically, environmentally and socially acceptable manner that meets the demands of an increasing population, and (2) optimizing and ensuring responsible and sustainable use of water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the poultry microbiome with data analytics</title>
      <link>/project/project4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project4/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding environmental and management factors contributing to pre-weaning mortality in hogs</title>
      <link>/project/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project2/</guid>
      <description>The P4 fellow who works on this project will analyze key performance indicators, data on environmental conditions in swine barns, and statistics on pre-weaning mortality across six hog farms spread throughout the SE U.S. The goal of the project will be to identify correlations between environmental and performance factors and hog mortality in order to provide data-driven improvements to swine farm management. The student who works on this project will regularly interact with a producer and engage in Extension.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>